<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DL</title>
    <link>https://darwinleung.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 12:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://darwinleung.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How does imputation work</title>
      <link>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-05-12-imputation-sklearn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-05-12-imputation-sklearn/</guid>
      <description>How does imputation work? Imputation is a pre-processing technique to handle missing data before fitting the data into model. One of the simplest implementation is to estimate the missing values using the mean/median or the most frequent value of the row/ column where the missing values are located. There are more advanced ways to impute data like regressions, multiple imputation etc.
Imputer in sklearn The Imputer function in the sklearn library is commonly used in various tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracting features from text - BoW, tfidf</title>
      <link>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-05-09-extracting-features-from-text-bow-tfidf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-05-09-extracting-features-from-text-bow-tfidf/</guid>
      <description>Extracting features from text Bag-of-words TF-IDF  Term-frequency-inverse document frequency Numeriacal statistics to reflect how important a word is to a document Used as weighting factor in text mining, it can also be used to generate word vector/ matrix representation Increase proportionally to the number of times a word appears in the document offset by the frequency of the word in the corpus  $$ tfidf(t,d,D) = tf(t,d) * idf(t,D) $$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Math in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-04-18-writing-math-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-04-18-writing-math-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>In this blog, I am going to write a lot of math. I used Typora as my markdown editor and it supports MathJax out of the box. I just need to wrap my math blocks with $$ (following this reference). However, I will need to do a quick step to make Hugo work with MathJax as discribed in the Hugo documentation. I copied add-mathjax-to-page.html and pasted in the beginning of post_footer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB for Developer M101P notes</title>
      <link>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-04-10-mongodb-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-04-10-mongodb-notes/</guid>
      <description>insertMany(), default ordered: true, once it encounters as error, insert stop. If ordered set to false, it will insert the rest of documents despite any errors.
 ObjectId: 12-Byte Hex string
_ _ _ _ , _ _ _ , _ _ , _ _ _
Date (time stamp), Mac addr, PID (process ID), Counter
 Exact match on array field example: db.movieDetails.find({&amp;ldquo;writers&amp;rdquo;: [&amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo;]}).count(), ordering matters. To find a match within array: db.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL optimization with indexing - part 3 - multi-column index</title>
      <link>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-04-04-sql-optimization-with-indexing-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-04-04-sql-optimization-with-indexing-part-2/</guid>
      <description>MySQL can only use one index for each SELECT statement, it is very common to perform operations on multiple columns like:
SELECT gaAppIds, dimension_date, dimension_country, dimension_source, dimension_medium, SUM(metric_sessions) FROM country_analytics GROUP BY gaAppIds , dimension_date , dimension_source , dimension_medium , dimension_country; By using a single-column index, we cannot take the full advantage for this query. We can add index for multiple columns (up to 16 columns). In the example above, we can add the following index with the 5 columns in the GROUP BY :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL optimization with indexing - part 2 - index types in MySQL</title>
      <link>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-04-03-sql-optimization-with-indexing-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-04-03-sql-optimization-with-indexing-part-2/</guid>
      <description>There are 2 main data structures for index in MySQL, they are B-tree and hash table. They are also the main index structures for other RMDBS.
B-tree B-tree is a self-balancing sorted data structure similar to a binary search tree. The only difference is that a node in B-tree can have more than 2 children. For me, it looks like a binary tree with a range of numbers in each node (vs only 1 number in a node).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL optimization with indexing - part 1</title>
      <link>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-04-02-sql-optimization-with-indexing-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-04-02-sql-optimization-with-indexing-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Knowing how to write a query is not enough, when our tables grow larger it is common to run into query performance issues. If we know in advance how we are querying the table, one very handful technique to &amp;ldquo;magically&amp;rdquo; speed up the query is to add appropriate indexes in tables.
What is index? From MySQL documentation:
 Indexes are used to find rows with specific column values quickly. Without an index, MySQL must begin with the first row and then read through the entire table to find the relevant rows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handy SQL Queries</title>
      <link>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-04-01-handy-sql-queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-04-01-handy-sql-queries/</guid>
      <description>This is a list of handy SQL queries I use, I will keep it updated occasionally.
Getting table sizes in MySQL This query lists the size of every table in every database in an MySQL instance, size sorted desc in MB:
SELECT table_schema as `Database`, table_name AS `Table`, round(((data_length + index_length) / 1024 / 1024), 2) `Size in MB` FROM information_schema.TABLES ORDER BY (data_length + index_length) DESC;	 ref: SO</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running python 2 and 3 using conda</title>
      <link>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-03-30-running-python-2-and-3-using-conda/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 12:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-03-30-running-python-2-and-3-using-conda/</guid>
      <description>I am taking the M101P course to brush up my Mongo skill, the course is kind of dated, it uses Python 2. However, I use Python 3 on my machine by default. I need a quick and easy way to run python 2 scripts without changing my default settings/path. I found conda offer a great out-of-box solution by using environment.
 A conda environment is a directory that contains a specific collection of conda packages that you have installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limbo</title>
      <link>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-03-26-limbo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 22:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-03-26-limbo/</guid>
      <description>We finished a indie game called &amp;ldquo;Limbo&amp;rdquo; over the weekend. Personally I like it very much, It is a short, simple, monochrome, 2D puzzle solving game. Although there is no exciting story or flashy graphic, the music and animation is outstanding, puzzles are well designed, it kept us engaged for hours.
I bought this game long time ago, never get time to try it until this Saturday I was downloading another large game, I decided to give it a try while we wait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up this blog with Hugo and Hyde-hyde</title>
      <link>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-03-25-setting-up-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 14:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darwinleung.github.io/posts/2018-03-25-setting-up-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>Hugo First, I follow the quick start guide to install and set up a hugo server locally.
Adding content Use hugo new posts/my-first-post.md or simply add a markdown file under the content\posts folder. Make sure the markdown files include the front matter, in a regular post page, it looks something like:
title: &amp;quot;Setting up this blog&amp;quot; date: 2018-03-25T14:47:00-04:00 draft: false tags: [ &amp;quot;hugo&amp;quot; , &amp;quot;git&amp;quot; ] categories: [ &amp;quot;programming&amp;quot; ]  For a static page like &amp;ldquo;About&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Contact&amp;rdquo;, I only use title and draft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://darwinleung.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darwinleung.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Darwin Leung, I am an aspiring data scientist based in Toronto, ON, Canada.
I am working at Shared as a data science engineer.
I studied Statistics at the University of Waterloo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://darwinleung.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://darwinleung.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Website: https://darwinleung.github.io
Email: darwinlkh@gmail.com</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>